don't worry we're gonna start the
episode soon i promise it's just raining
outside and i don't record when it rains
come on
two minutes later
still raining three minutes later
you know what i've
just given up five minutes later you
know what we're gonna wait this out in
my office i better bring my bed
still raining ah that blew up the bed
gonna go and sleep at the barge then no
we still can't sleep this is literal
what's happening
i just want it to stop raining i don't
think i've ever had such an awful start
to an episode
wow well that was just the worst
at least we can finally start the
episode now
so what are we doing today we have got a
very very busy day and by busy i'm gonna
be busy b today well what i've got in
mind is the largest best
and final form
of the barge i know that we've been
focusing on the barge but it is a
project that we need to see through to
the end and every minute i'm working on
this i'm not working on the back of the
mansion so what we've got is obviously
our badge now this hasn't changed in an
extraordinarily long time i have been on
my creative world
working out what the next stage is oh
cool now it wants to be night so i've
been working pretty hard between the
last episode and this episode designing
the final barge form and also
doing some work to the big barge sweep i
know that there's a lot of excitement
about this and some really good ideas
about how to make this work
but
after making and finishing this little
tunnel
that we started in the last episode i
realized that this is no small project
and i have messaged impulse who is
technically a partner company of the
barge
but i realized very quickly
that the timings of this is going to be
extraordinarily
difficult so
what i've been doing between the
episodes is working out all of the
timings and i finalized a disc and music
for
this project so without further ado
let's get in to playing this disc and
seeing or feeling what this game will
start like when people come and play so
they'll put in their 10 diamonds in the
chest they'll play the disc and that
will set the cart in motion so let's do
a very quick run through welcome to the
hc bbs the hermitcraft big badge sweep
your task is simple open shulker boxes
and grab items here's the shulker box
coming up now see if you can open it
oh dear it's empty the ones coming up
though won't be your task is to grab as
many items as possible but here's the
catch you have extremely limited time
don't dawdle and make sure you look
around
looks like you're about to begin
good luck
so then you get straight into
the actual thing man that's quite loud
actually
i might need to mess with the the levels
of the song a little bit but you get an
idea you then go round the whole thing
and end up finishing at the barge but
here's the thing the song actually lasts
way longer
than this
it actually goes on for a whole other
minute a whole minute you can hear it
slightly so the music has gone on for at
least another minute and it does go on
for quite a long time
so
i need to come up with a plan
[Music]
okay so we need to come up with a plan
basically it's uh quite a long song now
i have two options i can either make the
track as long as the song or
i can make the track and then cut the
song to match the track so what this
basically means is if i'm doing the
track first
i really need to start building the
barge
first i need to complete what's going to
be up here at the top layer before i can
go ahead and start making all this
so
that's basically what we're gonna start
with today we're gonna
try and get a lot of the hcbbs done
today but i assure you it probably won't
be
and to kick things off we really really
need to get the barge upgraded and this
is no
this is no small task we've got
what i have in mind for the barge is
quite exceptional this is going to be at
least a full day's building
so
i say we stop blabbing about it and
actually get building so
let's
go
[Music]
i'm really sorry but i actually have to
cut this short because impulse has got
back to me and is going to meet with me
now hello impulse hello green i have
asked for a meeting for actually do you
know what come with come come up to my
office i built this office we're going
to use it uh yeah i'll see you up there
dangerous
didn't you lose all your stuff in this
thing no it's 100 percent safe it's just
not it's not 100 foolproof as scott
are you sure oh oh okay okay okay
okay okay that was scary okay all right
well welcome welcome to the barge co uh
the reason i've asked you here today is
because actually i need some help and
technically you are a partner in the
bargeco family that's true yeah all
right so are you interested uh sure i'm
always interested all right i'm gonna
have to take this up with my superior
wait wait wait we have to come over to
the the real office what is it this
bridge isn't very okay right well
wonderful we've now got an appointment
with the ceo
okay very that was just the assistant i
see
very nice very nice oh there's even more
diamonds than this one i need more
employees okay
so what i'm working on at the moment is
called the hc bbs which is the
hermitcraft big barge sweep it's a mini
game where you have to grab lots of
stuff
and okay basically i've bitten off a bit
more than i can chew and it would be
great to get someone else involved to
make this better okay all right i mean
minigames that means like
it's not it's it's not a mini game it's
not well whoa no yeah we don't use the
minigame word here okay
it's a shopping experience
oh
okay okay yeah it's a show it's a
shopping experience if it's a mini game
people might expect to play for free
you see you see how that works okay
right
because you need more diamonds yeah
right i do i do
i i need more chandeliers
okay right so
it's best that i just show you so if you
just batman off this with me you don't
need to see the full experience again on
the minecart you already went through it
once so let's just skip to the end but
that's the concept i probably fooled you
into thinking it was a full experience i
thought i thought i was getting good
stuff here yeah no no not at all so
basically this is the track and as you
can imagine there will be loads of
shulker boxes everywhere and you've got
to grab stuff all right and then okay
okay and then you gotta uh pay to enter
and that's that's how you make money but
it's gonna be really tough because the
minecart goes quick
yeah what kind of stuff are you gonna be
putting in mostly junk
good idea i was gonna say because you
could like lose profit if you put good
stuff in there like quartz i'll be
honest with you most of the stuff that's
going in the shulker boxes are the stuff
that i've excavated digging this hole
really oh okay there you go wait a
minute wait a minute
what happened to my little barge with
the impulse yeah i'm currently in the
process of building
the uh the barge expansion so
i've put off impulse buys for a long
time and impulse buys is getting its own
little place up but i've had to leave
those there just just in case someone
still needs it
okay i mean kind of a difficult shopping
experience but it works at least it's
still available
okay so what do you need help with then
so what i'm thinking is basically giving
you a segment of this track to do to
decorate and to maybe do some redstone
and extravaganza you know like
sending them up on slime blocks and
timings and things that i'm probably no
good at fun stuff yes fun stuff ooh
bouncing them around like a pinball that
sounds amazing exactly okay i don't know
dig dig off a section that lasts about
30 seconds and then rejoin here at some
point oh yeah yeah sure okay i can cut
off out here take them around a little
bit bounce them around like you said and
then we'll just come back in and finish
the loop and it'll be great man yeah i'm
down that sounds like so much fun okay
this is going to be a brilliant i i
can't wait for people in space because
i'm pretty sure everyone's going to sign
up and then they're going to be
disappointed there will be some rare
stuff and there will be some valuable
stuff as well but of course it's gonna
be some of the harder things to get if
you just grab the closest thing to you
you're probably gonna end up with junk
i'm helping is there any benefit for me
like so my my idea was that the
barge sweep ends at impulse buys because
it's like you're leaving
do you know what it is that's what i'm
talking about yes okay perfect so
definitely some benefit for me as well
in this i like that exactly oh man yeah
i am 100 in i have already got some
designs swirling in my head so i'm gonna
get straight to work on this wicked i'm
gonna get back to building this because
i was halfway through it and now we've
had our meeting with impulse and he's
agreed to get involved let's get back to
the time lapse where we finish
the enormous barge upgrade
[Music]
after many hours
much grinding
and a couple of tears
we have finally created
the final form of the barge
look at it in all its glory i am not
going to be improving this anymore i am
happy with how this looks and has come
out so let's have a little bit of a tour
of the final barge
so from the outside it basically has
gotten a little bit taller we've got
this large section on the side which we
all know what that's for but what have i
done to the main structure well it has
got bigger
but not actually in any meaningful way
so the inside although it looks as well
it's pretty much identical in the on the
inside you do get this rather nice look
up in the courtyard because one thing is
for sure i know i know me and i know the
people of this server and we don't like
to use doors too much most people prefer
to be able to fly
into the middle of a shop just because
doors are for me to collect not to build
so it does mean that i need to shift
some things around i need to move all of
my logs into this section so this part
of the barge is not actually going to be
for
uh the mini game shouldn't call it a
mini game for the shopping experience so
what's gonna happen is that is the track
is gonna go all the way down there it's
gonna make its way up here so when they
finally get to the end this will be
where impulse buys is so he can put his
stock here and
whatever he wants and then they are kind
of forced they there's no other way to
go back through the barge
and buy whatever they want although they
should come out with a bunch of goodies
as well i was thinking that i should put
a couple
diamond chandeliers hanging here there's
a perfect opportunity for another couple
of diamond chandeliers can't get enough
of them i'll tell you what i've had
quite enough of building in this style
and the barge for a while and it is also
i think one of the largest shops in the
shopping district it definitely at least
stands out
so compared to the other shops here oh
it's kind of in competition with scar
shop over here but it's certainly bigger
than town hall enough about the barge
but also not enough about the barge
because i've run out of sand again i i
don't know why this started but etho for
some reason said if you're still using a
shovel to collect sand
you're a sucker and i need to verify
these claims because i have definitely
been using a shovel
for a very long time and why i don't
want to be a sucker so we're gonna do a
little bit of an experiment and we're
gonna find out the fastest way to
collect sand according to etho using tnt
is the fastest way to collect sand what
is this here's some sea pickles to
brighten your day give some to your
friends so they have a good day
or else pickles
i don't need pickles all right i'll give
some to a friend anyway let's stay on
task it's very easy to get distracted on
hermitcraft so we're going to go armed
with a full box of gunpowder to the
desert before we do this experiment
because i want to factor in the cost of
mining sand to make tnt
into the calculations so let's head over
to my private desert where we're going
to collect a whole bunch of sand for
about an hour and we're going to figure
out whether i'm the sucker
or ethos the sucker was it loser it was
something like that so my private desert
is all the way by the upside down which
i've not visited in a really long time
and mainly because of this enormously
large tunnel so i'm thinking we're gonna
do about half an hour
of collecting for each method and see
how we do what the heck
there's bees in my tunnel
yo
what
someone explain
right now
how
how do bees
they don't spawn in the nether they
don't spawn in the nether there's one
two
three
there's so there's four or five bees
here
this is a mystery there's no portal
around here and we're in the middle of
my upside down tunnel i mean you can't i
don't have my cat my minecraft character
doesn't have a mouth but in real life my
mouth is open i where did these bees
come from they say that the bees are
disappearing i found them they're in my
minecraft nether tunnel
someone explain this makes no sense
okay we're just gonna fly past that that
is really weird all right to the desert
we go ah the upside down
a beautiful build that was abandoned
because that turns out that the nether
is not actually that fun to be in but i
we can we appreciate for a second just
the upside down mansion i it is a
magnificent build to my private desert
we go here we are so we're gonna do two
time lapses okay
half an hour of tnt collecting
and half an hour of normal netherrite
shovel collecting so let's just do a a
quick experiment first just with normal
tnt because i need to make sure that i
actually use the tnt in the most
effective way for this test to work so
let's just do
first of all i guess we can do a surface
level tnt and see what that produces
so that pretty much goes from the top
all the way down to
the sandstone level
and we get a lot of sand okay but i need
to factor in the cost
of using tnt to collect sand and then
using that sand again to craft more tnt
i have a feeling that i've i'm a sucker
i'm not gonna i'm not gonna i just just
saw how much sand that that created
and i'm now thinking that i might
etho might be right
we're gonna find out okay so let's do
the first half an hour just using a
shovel and see how that works
[Music]
i should do grind experiments like this
more often because i actually got some
very valuable information okay so turns
out i'm a loser according to etho he was
right it is way more efficient to use
tnt assuming that you have the gun
powder ready and not the tnt
than it is to use a shovel shovel's got
245 stacks in 30 minutes and tnt got 329
this is closer than i thought it was
going to be i actually thought tnt may
even double it but it turns out 84 extra
stacks and that means that the shovel is
8.1 stacks per minute and the tnt is
10.9 stacks per minute but i have to
tell you something even though the tnt
resulted in more stacks of sand
well
it's a lot messier it is a lot look at
this i didn't place them particularly
strategically because i wanted to make
sure that i was going to not blow up any
of the items with the tnt on the ground
to be as efficient as possible not only
does tnt look worse it was actually way
less fun i had a more
enjoyable time using shovels than i did
tnt so
there's a trade-off
tnt definitely more efficient
but using shovels results in a cleaner
desert
and a probably more enjoyable time but
that's that's just my personal opinion
so experiment over we ended up with
more than enough stock for the barge i
can tell you that much
so let's ship this all the way back
to the shopping district oh and tnt also
you end up with a bunch of byproduct of
sandstone which you wouldn't normally
get
with normal shovels so i don't know if
that's a benefit or a hindrance but you
end up with some extra stuff wow i
really didn't bring enough shulker boxes
for this okay well i've got enough to
stock up the barge and that's what we
came for so let's head back to the
shopping district and get this all
stocked up oh that's better having empty
chests in the barge makes me feel a
little bit nauseous
okay well we got actually a pretty good
stock of sand
speaking of etho there is something
that's popped up right over here that
etho has announced is open for business
so i thought we'd have a little go brain
ee's trivia
theme minecraft prize spruce logs now we
can always use
more spruce logs place your diamonds in
the shulker box near this lectern look
in the shulker box that appears and read
the question
choose and toss the one item from the
shulker box that best answers the
question into the hopper in front of you
this sounds way more complicated now
that i'm reading reading it
hover your mouse over the cursor press q
the lights turn off when the system is
out of questions check back later okay
let's just give this a go
place diamonds in here how many diamonds
doesn't
it doesn't say how many diamonds okay i
just checked i checked discord and it is
just one diamond so you put your diamond
in not found in a desert temple
oh boy
really i'm going to guess it's oh
it's got to be smooth sandstone right
yay
we get we get our diamond back and we
get some spruce logs oh this is amazing
okay okay i'm gonna test out my trivia
my my minecraft trivia knowledge here we
go
max ancient debris veins per chunk
that's two that's gotta be that's two
yay i turned out i know some minecraft
i've only been playing it for 10 years
alright let's try again
splash water bottles don't hurt enderman
uh
i think that's the end of the episode
guys uh
got a bit too big for my boots there
of course of course waters
bye